So, I know that we've gone through all this and some of you might be thinking,
well, who builds web apps this way?
Because after all, every modern text that you'll see always talks about
build tools and that kind of thing.
To be honest, progressive enhancement is very much a thing that
continues to exist to this day even though it's not talked about a lot.
Code read writes are very sexy,
but the truth is when you're dealing with enterprise systems,
it's just not realistic to stop everything as we talked about before and write new features.
But dropping in the CDN with view,
having it progressively enhanced, that all works.
Because we're not going to cover it at this point because we're going to move into build tools.
But a lot of these things we're seeing here,
they can be just abstracted into .js files.
You can actually modularize your code.
You can do a lot actually and make a fairly robust app.
It doesn't have to all live inside of this single object that I've shown you all.
That's just a way for us to keep it all as a mental model.
But eventually, you can break it out,
import .js into here, use it like it can still scale pretty darn well.
So this image here, which I love is like the cake,
that then you get the frosting, then you get the candles.
So the credit here is a Tiffany say,
this is our blog post on what is progressive enhancement and why should you care.
So definitely something that I do think modern web developers need to
consider when it comes to the realities of upgrading their code base.
So this is a smashing article magazine by
Sarah Drasner who used to be on the View Core team.
This is a great one because the title of this is
Replacing jQuery with View.js, no build step necessary.
This is also a very valid way of using View.
It's like if you know that only one page on your entire app,
because you're statically generating it so everything's on the server side,
but only one could use some interactivity,
don't even need jQuery anymore.
You could literally just drop View because I believe the CDN site is either roughly the same,
if View is not slightly lower at this point,
but that is actually a viable option now.
You don't need to even approach View as a framework.
You can be just little bits of interactivity that are sprinkled in an app.
Finally, again, people always get the idea like,
well, who's actually done it this way?
Well, GitLab did it this way.
GitLab used to actually be a Ruby on Rails app.
It was super-length. So if anyone works with Ruby on Rails,
you know that especially back then,
integrating node-based tool chains into that was extremely painful.
Again, and also they needed to ship features.
This was before they went public.
They had customers they needed to meet the needs.
So they couldn't stop everything and go,
yeah, Rails is outdated.
We really would love to use a framework,
so let's stop building stuff.
They couldn't do that. So what did they do?
I'm trying to remember actually which page it was.
I knew someone who was on the team that did this.
Let's just, for example,
they had the sign-in page and they said on the sign-in page,
let's add view as a CDN and let's just add interactivity.
Once they proved that that worked well,
they went, okay, next one.
What's something we can hit that's fairly low-impact
performance-wise that we can do?
I think there was another one that they did.
Basically, that's what they did.
They slowly added new features to the customer base
while progressively migrating their app to view.
Then eventually, when they had the tipping point of like,
they had so much code in view that it made sense to like,
let's take a couple of weeks to like refactor our code
to actually use the node tooling to like bring it all in.
That's when they actually did that,
but they proved their case rather than trying to just tell product,
hey, just stop. We have this wonderful idea that
if anyone has done ever a massive app refactoring,
it often doesn't go quite as planned.
Then deadlines get pushed,
but they were able to realistic do that.
And so that's how GitLab is now running on view now.
And so the reason I wanted to emphasize this method is
because it's something that I think is often overlooked
when people are thinking about recommending solutions to clients.
And it's something that I want people to know about
so whenever you're working for someone
or you think that this could be a good approach,
you now know that this is here for you.